Honglin CHEN

38 Zheda Road, Xihu District, Hangzhou City, Zhejiang Province, P. R. China 310027 (+86)159-8936-1915 o honglinchen1997@outlook.com o homepage o github

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests mainly focus on Computer Graphics, especially on numerical optimization and its applications on visual computing problems, e.g. physics-based simulation and digital fabrication.

Most of my recent work is related to physics-based simulation, while a bunch of other topics remain attractive to me, including the application of machine learning on simulation and shape modeling.

EDUCATION

JUN 2019 (Expected) SEP 2015

B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology

College of Computer Science & Technology **Zhejiang University**, Hangzhou, China

OVERALL GPA: 3.89/4.0(87.3/100) | MAJOR GPA: 3.89/4.0

SEP 2017-DEC 2017

Exchange Student

Department of Computer Science

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov 2018 - Current

Development Intern

INTERNET GRAPHICS GROUP, Microsoft Research Asia
Project: Soft Pneumatic Model | Mentor: Yizhong Zhang

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Current

Undergraduate Research Intern

APR 2018 | STATE KEY LAB OF CAD&CG, Zhejiang University

Final Year Thesis: Constitutive model approximation using volume

graph | Advisor: Jin Huang

JUL-SEP 2018

Summer Research Intern

MULTIMEDIA AND INTERACTIVE COMPUTING LAB, Nanyang Technological

Jniversity

Project: Interactive Material Design | Advisor: Jianmin Zheng

OCT 2017-MAR 2018

Research Trainee

STUDENT RESEARCH TRAINING PROGRAM, Zhejiang University

Project: Cloth Simulation | Advisor: Kun Zhou

SELECTED PROJECTS

JUL-CURRENT 2018 | Interactive Material Editor

Advisor: Jianmin Zheng

An open-source interactive material editor supporting global Young Modulus optimization and visualization based on force and displacement input.(source)

Reference: Interactive Material Design using Model Reduction, Siggraph 2015

MAR-JUN 2018 | Animation based on Embedded Deformation

Course: Advance in Computer Graphics | Advisor: Kun Zhou/Zhong Ren

Project ranked top 1% (99.0/100)

An open-source interactive solution for object animation. (source)
Reference: Embedded Deformation for Model Reduction, Siggraph 2007

IAN-MAR 2018 | Cloth Simulation

A simple cloth simulator based on mass-spring model. (demo)

Implement collision detection and response.

Reference: Robust treatment of collisions, contact and friction for cloth animation, Siggraph 2002 and Simulation of clothing with folds and wrinkles, Eurographics 2003

JUL 2017 | Mini Scientific Calculator

A simple open-source scientific calculator following MVVM model. (source)

Implement algorithms of calculating conditional number, solving matrix equation, polynomial equation, integral and ordinary differential equation, cubic spline and creating line chart.

HONORS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

First Class Academic Scholarship(Top 5% in Academic Performance)	2016
Distinctive Student Awards	2016
Scholarship of the Government of Zhejiang Province	2016
Scholarship of Arts and Athletics	2016
Scholarship of Arts and Athletics	2017

LANGUAGE & SKILLS

ENGLISH: TOEFL score: 108 (R: 30 L:29 S:22 W:27)

GRE score (V: 157 Q: 170 AW: 4.0)

PROGRAMMING SKILL: C++(primary language): abundant experience with Linux+Cmake and QT,

familiar with major open-source graphics library(Eigen, Libigl, Vegas,

Tetgen, VCGlib), OpenGL and GLSL

OPENCV(familiar) LATEX(good) GIT(good) PYTHON(average)
ASSEMBLY LANGUAGE(average) ERLANG(average) CUDA C(limited)

GRAPHICS SOFTWARE: MESHLAB(familiar) BLENDER(familiar) UNITY3D(limited)

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

I enjoy long-distance running and run pretty fast.

Related Prizes

1-st prize winner at the women's 3000 m, Sports meeting of Zhejiang University Nov.2015 2-nd prize winner at the women's 1500 m, Sports meeting of Zhejiang University Nov.2015